CARLOS L BAEZ

A self-directed professional with customer relations, financial and procurement programs management expertise, seeks to bring talent, and performance to a respected organization that values drive, energy, and dedication to achieve results. Demonstrates strong performance skills that improve team work efficiencies, enhance productivity, and contribute to long-term sustainable business growth.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Interpersonal Skills
- Budget Analysis
- Quality Assurance
- Python Scripting/Software
- Secret Security Clearance
- Financial Management
- Accounting & Procurement
- Django Web Framework
- Client Relations
- Strategic Planning
- Project Management
- Bootstrap Technology

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INDEPENDENT DEVELOPER, Florida

03/2018 - PRESENT

Colaborate with clients/partners in development of brand identity, clean and simple intuitive user interface.

INDEPENDENT FREELANCER

Created simple web page layout for clients in the film/government industry.

Key Accomplishments:

- Designed database system with Django Web Framework.
- Create Virtual Environments to implement, and manage multiple software systems.

CONSTELLIS, Afghanistan

12/2010 to 02/2018

A leading provider of global high threat security services with an array of trained specialist in defense and medical support operations.

Senior Guard Shift Supervisor/Firearms Instructor

 Managed all aspects of 80+ team for personal and group protection detail in high target threat regions with oversight of \$10M+ in government facilities and high value budgets.

Key Accomplishments:

- Coordinated and monitored project teams, while providing technical and analytical support to meet demands.
- Managed field operations at multiple sites and department functions with a focus on cost controls and timeline directives.
- Acted as liaison between technical and non-technical cross-functional teams, inclusive of vendors and clients to improve project management coordination and information conveyance.

JB GLOBAL SOLUTIONS, Iraq

07/2009 to 09/2010

A regional provider of project management, construction, and maintenance services in the Middle Eastern country of Iraq.

Project Manager/Director

 Managed \$1.2M operation and maintenance contract for services to the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq with budgeting and costing, forecasting, security, specialty service functions, and operations demands.

Key Accomplishments:

- Collaborated with Executive Committee and Board of Directors of PAE to meet strategic human resource deficiencies, re-align as deemed necessary to meet impromptu demands, and achieve business financial objectives.
- Directed and coordinated deliverables with staff members, cross-functional departments, and vendors to meet or exceed project goals and objectives.
- Adjusts scope or resources as appropriate; Mitigates potential risk to the project.

CARLOS L BAEZ 2

ACADEMI, IRAQ 08/2006 to 06/2009

A global security services firm providing personal and group protection in high target threat regions and locales with a focus on Middle Eastern and southwest Asia detail.

Security Specialist

 Provided personal protection to United States Diplomats in multiple international locations, while engaging in strategic planning and analysis for key regional embassy facility security.

Key Accomplishments:

- Actively participated in group crisis response team to develop strategic plans for U.S. Embassy security and mitigate long-term risks.
- Engaged in group security detail for President, Vice-President, and Secretary of State, inclusive of key strategic planning and adherence to secret service protocols.

U.S. MARINE CORP, Camp Lejeune, NC

11/2001 to 11/2005

A branch of the United States Armed Forces focused on marine and related theatres of engagement and defense.

USMC, E-5 Sergeant

 Charged with oversight of training elite marines for special operations, new recruits, and existing service members to meet long-term military objectives and immediate operations demands.

Key Accomplishments:

- Oversaw crisis response team of 9 highly skilled marines to ensure readiness and expedited movement to key engagement zones or assigned theatre of operations.
- Collaborated with specialized Marines to train and coach 400+ recruits and existing service members to fill gaps in critical skills, and acclimate to Middle Eastern theater of operations directives.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer, Lambda School, San Francisco, CA 2021
M.B.A., Project Management, University of Management & Technology, Arlington, VA 2015
B.B.A., General Management, University of Management & Technology, Arlington, VA 2008
A.B.A., General Management, University of Management & Technology, Arlington, VA 2006
HS Diploma, Majored: Architecture, Saunders Trade & Technical High School, Yonkers, NY 1998

AWARDS & DISTINCTIONS

U.S. Military, United States Marine Corp, Honorable DischargeU.S. Military, United States Marine Corp, Letter of RecommendationU.S. Training Center/Academi, Afghanistan, Recognition Award